

# TUOMAS TAJAKKA

PHD, MATHEMATICIAN

### Contact



+358-50-5381417



tuomas.tajakka@gmail.com



ttajakka.github.io



linkedin.com/in/tuomas-tajakka

### 公 Skills

Mathematics
Problem solving
Scientific communication
Web development

## Programming basics

C/C++, Python, R, Mathematica HTML/CSS/JavaScript, React

### C Languages

Fluency: Finnish, English Basics: Swedish, German

### About me

A lifelong lover of math, I aim to tackle complex problems and help make data-driven decisions in industry and the public sector. To achieve this, I apply strong logical, quantitative, and communications skills obtained as a researcher mathematician. Besides academic work, I have gained technical skills in web development and data science through courses and personal projects.

### Education

#### PhD in mathematics

2015 - 2021

University of Washington, Seattle, USA

### MSc in mathematics and physics

2008 - 2015

Aalto University, Espoo, Finland

### Work experience

### **Stockholm University**

2021-2023, Stockholm, Sweden

#### Postdoctoral researcher

- Conduct research in pure mathematics, communicate results via articles and presentations.
- Instructor for master's level class in cryptography.
- Mentor bachelor's thesis in error correcting codes.

### **University of Washington**

2015-2021, Seattle, WA, United States

#### **Doctoral candidate**

- Complete PhD thesis in algebraic geometry.
- Instructor and teaching assistant for a wide range of undergraduate classes in mathematics.
- Mentor undergraduate research and study projects.

### **Aalto University**

2010-2015, Espoo, Finland

#### Teaching and research assistant

- Teaching assistant for numerous bachelor and master level mathematics courses.
- Research assistant for mathematics and theoretical low temperature physics.

#### **CERN**

June-August 2011, Geneva, Switzerland

#### **Summer student**

· Analyze particle physics data using C++